Ellerbe, Harry. Papers (MS Thr 437): Guide.
Papers,
1924-1983.
Harvard Theatre Collection, Houghton Library, Harvard University
MS Thr 437
Ellerbe, Harry.
3 boxes and 9 scrapbooks (6 linear ft.)
Promptbooks, annotated plays, contracts, and other miscellaneous material of American actor and director Harry Ellerbe.
*2003MT-0137(b)
Gift of Mr. Harry Ellerbe, 1896 Wycliff Road, N.W. Atlanta, GA 30309; received: 1984 September 19.
Ellerbe (1901-1992) was an American actor and director.
Organized into the following series:
I. Promptbooks and annotated plays
II. Manuscripts
III. Clipping Files
IV. Photographs
V. Scrapbooks
VI. Playbills and other printed materials
Contains promptbooks and annotated plays; actors' equity contracts, 1930-1936; letters to Ellerbe; financial records; address books; clippings; photos; scrapbooks on his acting career; playbills of plays he acted in or directed; souvenir programs; and miscellaneous theatre flyers and other printed material.
- I. Promptbooks and annotated plays
  - Kelly, George. Phillip Goes Forth. Samuel French, 1931. Autographed copy., (1)
    Mr. Ellerbe created the role of Phillip.
  - King Arthur. TS. (mimeo) signed; Alliance Theatre, Atlanta, [n.d.]., (2)
  - Ibsen, Henrik. Ghosts. TS., signed; annotated in pencil and red ink. For Mme. Nazimova's production, 1935., (3)
  - Ibsen, Henrik. Ghosts. TS. signed; prepared from memory by Mr. Ellerbe, from Nazimova production, Empire Theatre, New York, 1935-1936., (4)
    Mr. Ellerbe appeared as Oswald.
  - Shaw, George Bernard. Heartbreak House. Actor's sides, annotated typescript, signed. Meadowbrook Theatre, Rochester, Michigan, 1971., (5)
  - Bolt, Robert. A Man for all Seasons. Actor's sides, annotated typescript, signed. Peachtree Playhouse, 1973., (6)
  - Williams, Tennessee. Summer and Smoke. Actor's sides, annotated typescript, signed. [n.p., 1973]., (7)
- II. Manuscripts
  - Actor's Equity contracts, 1930-1936., (8)
    For:
    Phillip Goes Forth, 1930
    The Tadpole, 1931
    The Men on Stilts, 1931
    Ghosts, 1936
    Ghosts/Hedda Gabler, 1936.
  - 32 letters to Harry Ellerbe from various correspondents, 1970-1983., (9)
    On opening nights.
  - Financial records., (10)
  - Address books, 1949 and n.d., (11)
  - Hancock, Mrs. Roy (nee Ellerbe) Letters to Harry Ellerbe, 1974., (12)
- III. Clipping Files
  - Obituaries of friends and colleagues., (13)
  - Reviews from Mr. Ellerbe's career, 1931-1981., (14)
  - Miscellaneous clippings from various Atlanta papers., (15)
  - Miscellaneous clippings, 1929-1983., (16)
  - Clippings related to Mr. Ellerbe's school years., (17)
  - Summer and Smoke, photocopies of reviews., (18)
- IV. Photographs
  - Folder of personal photographs, New York and Hollywood apartments., (19)
  - Folder of photographs and letters relating to Mr. Ellerbe's dog Billy., (20)
  - Album containing photographs of friends and colleagues, 1930-1980., (21)
  - Album of photographs from the productions of Ghosts and Hedda Gabler [1935-1936]., (22)
  - Album of photographs from Mr. Ellerbe's career; also includes programs and clippings., (23)
  - Folder of photographs of Alla Nazimova and Rudolf Valentino., (24)
  - Folder of personal photographs of Mr. Ellerbe, 1924-1973 and n.d., (25)
  - Folder of photographs of friends and colleagues., (26)
- V. Scrapbooks
  - 1 scrapbook relating to Mr. Ellerbe's acting career, compiled by a fan (with photocopy). 1930's., (27)
  - 9 personal scrapbooks of reviews and photographs from Mr. Ellerbe's career. 1926-1948., (28)
- VI. Playbills and other printed materials
  - Playbills of plays acted in:, (29)
    - 15 New York, 1936-1973.
    - 4 New York, n.d.
    - 14 Rochester, Michigan, 1970-1981.
    - 3 Rochester, Michigan, n.d.
    - 8 Atlanta and Columbus, Georgia, 1925-1973.
    - 1 Atlanta, Georgia, n.d.
    - 6 Springfield and Marblehead, Massachusetts, 1941-1975.
    - 3 Cape Cod, Massachusetts, 1973.
    - 4 Florida, 1973.
    - 2 Westport, Connecticut, 1973.
    - 2 Washington, DC, 1973.
    - 1 Hollywood, California, 1966.
    - 2 New Mexico, 1974.
    - 3 Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, 1976.
    - 2 Abington, Virginia, 1976.
  - Playbills of plays directed:, (30)
    - 3 Olney, Maryland, 1949-1951.
    - 2 Atlanta, Georgia, 1971-1972.
    - 3 Columbus, Georgia, 1973-1975.
    - 2 Springfield, Massachusetts, 1975.
    - 1 Rochester, Michigan, 1971.
    - 1 Hollywood, California, 1962.
    - 1 California, Ritz Theatre, n.d.
    - 1 Bermuda, n.d.
  - Souvenir programs:, (31)
    - An Evening with the Playwrights, Springer Opera House, [1976]., 2 copies.
    - King Arthur, Atlanta Repertory Theatre, 1968.
    - Oliver, Theatre of the Stars, 1970.
    - Camelot, Theatre of the Stars, 1969.
    - The Subject was Roses, Springer Opera House, 1978., 2 copies.
    - The Desk Set, Artist's Embassy, n.d., 2 copies.
    - Black Eyed Susan, Music Box Theatre, Hollywood, n.d.
  - Flyers from various theatres, 1971-1978 and n.d., (32)
  - Miscellaneous materials, (33)
    - Huntington Hartford Theatre, 1973.
    - Roundabout Theatre Company, The Show Off, 1977., 2 copies.
    - Actor's prayer from Linda Darnell, March 3, 1965.
  - The Theatre Magazine, 1913, (34); 2 vols.
  - Theatre World, 1944-1945., (35)
  - The American Stage of Today, New York, 1910., (36)
  - Who is that?, Warren B. Myers, New York, 1967., (37)